It was the middle of summer and well past closing time
كان ذلك في منتصف الصيف وفي الوقت الذي كنا فيه
in the downtown Berkeley bar where my friend Polly and I
في حانة بيركلي وسط المدينة كنت أنا وصديقتي بولي
worked together as bartenders.
نعمل معاً كساقيتين في الحانة.
Usually at the end of our shift we had a drink -- but not that night.
عادةً بعد نهاية الدوام نشرب الخمر -- لكن ليس في تلك الليلة.
"I'm pregnant.
" أنا حامل"
Not sure what I'm going to do yet," I told Polly.
"لا أعرف ما علي فعله" قلتُ لبولي.
Without hesitation, she replied, "I've had an abortion."
أجابتني دون أي تردد: "لقد قمتُ بعملية إجهاض في السابق."
Before Polly, no one had ever told me that she'd had an abortion.
قبل بولي لم تخبرني امرأة أنها قامت بعملية إجهاض.
I'd graduated from college just a few months earlier
كنت قد تخرجت من الجامعة قبل بضعة أشهر فقط
and I was in a new relationship when I found out that I was pregnant.
وقد كنت في علاقة جديدة عندما اكتشفَت بأني حامل.
When I thought about my choices, I honestly did not know how to decide,
عندما كنت أفكر بالخيارات المتاحة أمامي بصراحة لم أكن أعرف كيف أتخذ القرار
what criteria I should use.
ما المعايير المتبعة لاتخاذ القرار.
How would I know what the right decision was?
كيف لي أن أعرف ما هو القرار الصائب؟
I worried that I would regret an abortion later.
كنت قلقة أني قد أندم إذا قمت بعملية الإجهاض.
Coming of age on the beaches of Southern California,
بلغت سن الرشد وأنا على شواطئ جنوب كاليفورنيا،
I grew up in the middle of our nation's abortion wars.
فنشأت في خِضمّ صراع بلدنا القائم حول عملية الإجهاض.
I was born in a trailer on the third anniversary of Roe vs. Wade.
لقد ولدت في الذكرى السنوية الثالثة لقضية (Roe vs. Wade ).
Our community was surfing Christians.
كان مجتمعنا مجتمع راكبي أمواج مسيحيين.
We cared about God, the less fortunate, and the ocean.
مهتمين بالإمتثال لأوامر الله، والأقل حظاً، والمحيط.
Everyone was pro-life.
كان الجميع هناك ضد الإجهاض
As a kid, the idea of abortion made me so sad that I knew if I ever got pregnant
حين طفولتي، كانت فكرة الإجهاض تُحزنني. علمت بأني إذا حملت في يوم ما
I could never have one.
فلن أستطيع القيام بالإجهاض.
And then I did.
ولكنني قمتُ به.
It was a step towards the unknown.
كانت خطوة نحو المجهول
But Polly had given me a very special gift:
لكن بولي أعطتني هدية مميزة جدا:
the knowledge that I wasn't alone
لقد أخبرتني أنني لستُ الوحيدة
and the realization that abortion was something that we can talk about.
ومن ثم أدركت، أن عملية الإجهاض أمرٌ يمكننا التحدث عنه
Abortion is common.
أنّ عملية الإجهاض شائعة.
According to the Guttmacher Institute, one in three women in America
وفقاً لمؤسسة غاتماكر واحدة من كل ثلاث نساء في أميركا
will have an abortion in their lifetime.
ستخضع لعملية إجهاض واحدة على الاقل خلال حياتها.
But for the last few decades, the dialogue around abortion in the United States
لكن في العقود القليلة الأخيرة، الحوار حول الإجهاض في الولايات المتحدة
has left little room for anything beyond pro-life and pro-choice.
ترك فسحة صغيرة للجدال في أي شيء عدا معارضة أو مناصرة عملية الإجهاض
It's political and polarizing.
إنها السياسة، والاستقطاب.
But as much as abortion is hotly debated, it's still rare for us,
وبرغم كون الإجهاض من مواضيع النقاش الساخنة، إلاأنه يندر الحديث عنه،
whether as fellow women or even just as fellow people,
سواء مع امرأة، أو حتى مع أي شخص.
to talk with one another about the abortions that we have.
لا مجال للحديث مع شخص آخر حول الإجهاض الذي قمنا به.
There is a gap.
هناك فجوة.
Between what happens in politics and what happens in real life,
بين ما يحدث في عالم السياسة وما يحدث في الحياة الواقعية،
and in that gap, a battlefield mentality.
ويملأ تلك الفجوة عقلية المعركة،
An "are you with us or against us?" stance takes root.
مواقف متجذرة: هل أنت معنا أم ضدنا؟
This isn't just about abortion.
ولا يقتصر ذلك على الإجهاض.
There are so many important issues that we can't talk about.
هناك قضايا مهمة أخرى لا يمكننا الحديث عنها.
And so finding ways to shift the conflict to a place of conversation
لذا فإيجاد طريقة لتحويل هذا الصراع الى أرضية حوار
is the work of my life.
هو عمل حياتي.
There are two main ways to get started.
هناك طريقتان أساسيتان يمكنك أن تبدأ بهما.
One way is to listen closely.
الأولى هي الإنصات بعناية.
And the other way is to share stories.
والثانية هي مشاركة القصص.
So, 15 years ago, I cofounded an organization called Exhale
لذا، قبل 15 عاما،شاركتُ في تأسيس منظمة تدعى "ايكسهل"
to start listening to people who have had abortions.
وبدأنا بالإصغاء إلى أناس قاموا الإجهاض.
The first thing we did was create a talk-line, where women and men
أول شيء قمنا بفعله هو إنشاء خط للتواصل، يستطيع من خلاله النساء والرجال
could call to get emotional support.
الاتصال والحصول على الدعم العاطفي.
Free of judgment and politics, believe it or not, nothing like our sevice
بعيداً عن السياسة أو المحاكمة صدقوا أو لا تصدقوا، لا شيء مثل خدماتنا
had ever existed.
كان متوفراً قبل ذلك.
We needed a new framework that could hold all the experiences that we were
كنا بحاجة الى وضع إطار جديد بحيث يمكننا من الاحتفاظ بكل التجارب
hearing on our talk-line.
التي كنا نصغي لها عبر خط التواصل
The feminist who regrets her abortion.
مناصرة المرأة التي ندمت على الاجهاض.
The Catholic who is grateful for hers.
الكاثوليكية الممتنة لقيامها بالإجهاض.
The personal experiences that weren't fitting neatly into one box or the other.
التجارب الشخصية التي لم تتناسب بشكل جيد مع هذه التجارب أو تلك.
We didn't think it was right to ask women to pick a side.
لم نعتقد أنه من الصواب أن نسأل النساء أن تنحاز لجهة.
We wanted to show them that the whole world was on their side,
أردنا أن نريهم أن العالم بأسره يقف إلى جانبهم،
as they were going through this deeply personal experience.
فيما كانوا يمرون بهذه التجربة الشخصية العميقة.
So we invented "pro-voice."
لذا أنشأنا "الصوت الداعم."
Beyond abortion, pro-voice works on hard issues that we've struggled with globally
عدا الاجهاض، يعمل "الصوت الداعم" على قضايا صعبة
issues like immigration, religious tolerance, violence against women.
قضايا مثل الهجرة، و التسامح الديني، والعنف ضد المرأة.
It also works on deeply personal topics that might only matter to you
كما أنه يعمل على مواضيع شخصية عميقة قد لا تهم أحد غيرك
and your immediate family and friends.
وأصدقاءك وعائلتك المقربين فقط.
They have a terminal illness, their mother just died,
في حال كان لديهم مرض عضال. أو أمهاتهم قد توفين للتو،
they have a child with special needs and they can't talk about it.
إن كان لديهم طفل ذو احتياجات خاصة ولا يمكنهم التحدث عن الأمر،
Listening and storytelling are the hallmarks of pro-voice practice.
الاصغاء ورواية القصص هي السمة الرئيسة لــ " الصوت الداعم ."
Listening and storytelling.
الاصغاء وقص القصص.
That sounds pretty nice.
هذه الفكرة تبدو رائعة للغاية.
Sounds maybe, easy? We could all do that.
تبدو أنها سهلة! بإمكان أي شخص فعلها.
It's not easy. It's very hard.
إنها ليست سهلة. إنها صعبة للغاية.
Pro-voice is hard because we are talking about things everyone's fighting about
"الصوت الداعم" عمل صعب لأننا نتحدث حول أمور يتنازع الجميع حولها
or the things that no one wants to talk about.
أو أشياء لا يحب أحد التحدث عنها.
I wish I could tell you that when you decide to be pro-voice, that you'll find
وددت لو استطيع اخباركم أنك عندما تقرر أن تصبح "صوتا داعما" سوف تصادفك
beautiful moments of breakthrough and gardens full of flowers,
لحظات جميلة خلال عملك، حدائق مليئة بالزهور،
where listening and storytelling creates wonderful "a-ha" moments.
حيث أن الاستماع ومشاركة القصص، تخلق نوع من ردات فعل جميلة أثناء المحادثة
I wish I could tell you that there would be a feminist welcoming party for you,
وددت لو استطيع إخباركم بأنّ حفلة ترحيب نسويّة ستكون في استقبالكم،
or that there's a long-lost sisterhood of people who are just ready
وأن هناك مؤاخاة قد فقدت منذ فترة طويلة بين الناس الذين هم مستعدون
to have your back when you get slammed.
لمساندتك عندما تُنتَقد.
But it can be vulnerable and exhausting to tell our own stories
ولكن، يمكن أن يكون الحديث عن قصّتك مُرهقا ومصيبا بالضعف
when it feels like nobody cares.
عندما تشعر أن لا أحد يهتم لأمرك.
And if we truly listen to one another,
وإن كنا نُصغي بصدق لبعضنا البعض،
we will hear things that demand that we shift our own perceptions.
سنسمع أموراً تتطلب منا تغيير نظرتنا لأمور معينة.
There is no perfect time and there is no perfect place
لا يوجد وقت مناسب تماماً، ولا يوجد مكان مناسب تماماً،
to start a difficult conversation.
للبدء بمحادثات معقدة.
There's never a time when everyone will be on the same page, share the same lens,
لن يكون هناك وقت محدد ليكون الجميع على توافق، ويتشاركون نفس التصور،
or know the same history.
و يعرفون خلفيات بعضهم.
So, let's talk about listening and how to be a good listener.
لذا , سوف نتحدث حول الانصات وكيف نصبح مستمعين جيدين.
There's lots of ways to be a good listener and I'm going to give you just a couple.
هناك عدة طرق لتصبح مستمعا جيدا وسوف أعطيكم الآن طريقتين فقط .
One is to ask open-ended questions.
الأولى هو أن تسأل أسئلة مفتوحة.
You can ask yourself or someone that you know,
يمكن أن تسأل نفسك أو شخص تعرفه،
"How are you feeling?"
"كيف تشعر؟"
"What was that like?"
"كيف كان ذلك؟"
"What do you hope for, now?"
"ما الذي تتمناه الآن؟"
Another way to be a good listener is to use reflective language.
وهناك طريقة أخرى لتكون مستمعا جيدا هي استخدام لغة المتحدّث.
If someone is talking about their own personal experience,
إذاا كان هناك شخص يتحدث عن تجربته الشخصية،
use the words that they use.
استخدم التعابير التي يستخدمها
If someone is talking about an abortion and they say the word "baby,"
اذا كان هناك شخص يتحدث عن الإجهاض وقال كلمة "طفل صغير."
you can say "baby."
يمكنك أن تقول له "طفل صغير."
If they say "fetus," you can say "fetus."
إذا قال "جنين" يمكنك أن تقول له "جنين."
If someone describes themselves as gender queer to you,
إذا كان هناك شخص يصف نفسه على أنه مختلف جنسياً عنك،
you can say "gender queer."
يمكنك دعوتهم " أحرار الجنس"
If someone kind of looks like a he, but they say they're a she -- it's cool.
إذا كان هناك شخص يبدو أنه رجل لكن يصف نفسه على أنه أنثى.. شيء عادي
Call that person a she.
قم بمحادثته يصفة المؤنث.
When we reflect the language of the person who is sharing their own story,
عندما نستخدم نفس اللغة التي تحدث بها الشخص الذي يشاركنا قصتّه،
we are conveying that we are interested in understanding who they are
فإننا نعلمهم بأننا مهتمون بفهم ماهم عليه
and what they're going through.
وما يمرون به.
The same way that we hope people are interested in knowing us.
بقدر أملنا في أن يكون الآخرون مهتمين بمعرفتنا.
So, I'll never forget being in one of the Exhale counselor meetings,
لذا، لن أنسى أنني عندما حضرت أحد اجتماعات " إيكسهل " كمرشدة اجتماعية،
listening to a volunteer talk about how she was getting a lot of calls
استمعت إلى إحدى المتطوعات، تتحدث عن تلقيها الكثير من الاتصالات
from Christian women who were talking about God.
من نساء مسيحيات كنّ يتحدثن عن الرب.
Now, some of our volunteers are religious, but this particular one was not.
حسناً، بعض متطوعينا متدينون لكن هذه لم تكن كذالك.
At first, it felt a little weird for her to talk to callers about God.
في البداية، شعرت بغرابة بعض الشيء عند تحدثها عن الرب مع المتصلين.
So, she decided to get comfortable.
لذا قرّرت أن تعتاد ذلك.
And she stood in front of her mirror at home, and she said the word "God."
فوقفت أمام المرآة في منزلها، وقالت كلمة "الرب"
"God."
"الرب."
Over and over and over again until the word no longer felt strange
وكررتها عددة مرات حتى ـصبحت هذه الكلمة غير غريبة
coming out her mouth.
على لسانها لتنطق بها.
Saying the word God did not turn this volunteer into a Christian,
قول كلمة الرب لم تحوّل هذه المتطوعة إلى مسيحية،
but it did make her a much better listener of Christian women.
لكن جعلتها تحسن إصغائها ظغلى المرأة المسيحية
So, another way to be pro-voice is to share stories,
وهناك طريقة أخرى لتصبح "صوتا داعما" وهي مشاركة القصص،
and one risk that you take on, when you share your story with someone else,
والمخاطرة الوحيدة في هذا التحدي، هو أنك عندما تشارك قصتك مع شخص أخر
is that given the same set of circumstances as you
بأنهم، في مجموعة من الظروف المشابهة لظروفك،
they might actually make a different decision.
قد يقومون في الحقيقة باتخاذ قرارات مغايرة.
For example, if you're telling a story about your abortion,
على سبيل المثال، إذا كنتِ تتحدثين عن عملية الإجهاض الخاصة بكِ،
realize that she might have had the baby.
أدركي أنها قد تكون أنجبت الطفل.
She might have placed for adoption.
من الممكن أنها وضعته للتبني.
She might have told her parents and her partner -- or not.
من الممكن أنها أخبرت والديها وشريكها.. ومن الممكن أنها لم تفعل.
She might have felt relief and confidence, even though you felt sad and lost.
من الممكن أنها شعرت بالطمأنينة والارتياح، حتى ولو شعرت ظاانت بالحزن و الضياع.
This is okay.
لا مشكلة في هذا.
Empathy gets created the moment we imagine ourselves in someone else's shoes.
يخلق التعاطف حالة حيث نتخيل أنفسنا مكان الشخص الآخر.
It doesn't mean we all have to end up in the same place.
لا يعني هذا أن المطاف سينتهي بنا في نفس المكان.
It's not agreement, it's not sameness that pro-voice is after.
ليس هذا توافقا، ليس التشابه غاية "الصوت الداعم".
It creates a culture and a society that values what make us special and unique.
إنها تخلق ثقافة ومجتمع يقدر قيمة ما يجعلنا مميزين وفريدين.
It values what makes us human, our flaws and our imperfections.
تقدر ما يجعلنا بشر، أخطاؤنا وعيوبنا
And this way of thinking allows us to see our differences with respect,
وهذه الطريقة في التفكير تسمح لنا أن نرى اختلافاتنا باحترام،
instead of fear.
بدلاً من الخوف.
And it generates the empathy that we need
وتولد التعاطف الذي نحتاج إليه
to overcome all the ways that we try to hurt one another.
للتغلب على جميع السُبل التي نحاول أن نجرح بعضنا البعض من خلالها.
Stigma, shame, prejudice, discrimination, oppression.
العار والخزي والتحيز والتمييز والقمع.
Pro-voice is contagious, and the more it's practiced
"الصوت الداعم" معد، و كلما مارسناه
the more it spreads.
كلمّا انتشر.
So, last year I was pregnant again.
السنة الماضية كنتُ حاملا مرة أخرى.
This time I was looking forward to the birth of my son.
في هذه المرة كنت أتطلع إلى ولادة ابني.
And while pregnant, I had never been asked how I was feeling so much in all my life.
لم يسألني أحد كيف شعوري طوال حياتي، كما فعلوا في فترة حملي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And however I replied, whether I was feeling wonderful and excited
ومهما كان ردّي، سواء كنت أشعر بشعور رائع ومتحمسة
or scared and totally freaked out,
أو شعور بالخوف والذعر،
there was always someone there giving me a "been there" response.
كان هناك دائماً شخص ما يعطيني إجابة " مررتُ بذلك "
It was awesome.
كان شعوراً رائعاً.
It was a welcome, yet dramatic departure from what I experience
كان ترحيبا، وأيضا رحيلا درامياَ عما قمتُ باختباره
when I talk about my mixed feelings of my abortion.
عندما أتحدث عن مشاعري المختلطة حول الإجهاض.
Pro-voice is about the real stories of real people
يدور "الصوت الداعم" حول قصص حقيقية من أناس حقيقيين
making an impact on the way abortion
مما يعطي تأثيرا على طريقة التي يتم بها
and so many other politicized and stigmatized issues
فهم و مناقشة الإجهاض والكثير من القضايا
are understood and discussed.
المسيّسة والموصومة بالعار.
From sexuality and mental health to poverty and incarceration.
من الأمور الجنسية والصحة العقلية إلى الفقر والسجن.
Far beyond definition as single right or wrong decisions,
أبعد من تعريفها على أنها قرارات صائبة أو خاطئة ببساطة،
our experiences can exist on a spectrum.
تجاربنا يمكن أن توضع على طيف واسع.
Pro-voice focuses that conversation on human experience
"الصوت الداعم" يركز محادثاته على تجارب الإنسان
and it makes support and respect possible for all.
ويجعل الاحترام والدعم متوفرين للجميع.
Thank you.
شكراَ
(Applause)
(تصفيق)